(Toyohashi Roadside Station)
（道の駅豊橋）
(It's a drive-in along the highway that handles a wide variety of local ingredients and specialty products.)
（地元の食材や特産品を 広く扱っている）
(As the name suggests, it's typically a facility for cars, but...)
（その名の通り 通常は車向けの施設だが）
(Today, I took a series of buses to get here.)
（今日はバスを乗り継いでここまで来た）
(The reason I went to such lengths to come here is...)
（なぜそうまでしてここに来たかというと）
Um...
えーっと
I wonder if they've arrived yet.
あいつらもう来てるかな？
Oh, Nukkun!
あ、ぬっくん！
Oh, Yakishio, you must be tired.
おお 焼塩（やきしお） お疲れ
Why are you in such a hurry?
どうしたそんなに慌てて
Hey, can I borrow that water? I'll give it back later.
ねえその水 後で 返すからもらっていい？
I already drank some, though...
これ飲みかけだけど
That's fine, thanks!
大丈夫 ありがとうね
Hey, wait!
えっ おい！
She's as fast as ever.
って相変わらず速いな
If Yakishio is here, then...
焼塩がここにいるってことは
Oh, there she is.
あ いた
Hey, Komari.
おい小鞠（こまり）
There you are.
そこにいたのか？
Hey, are you okay?
おい大丈夫か？
(Uh...)
え…
(Komari looks like she's about to collapse, and I just got here.)
小鞠のやつ あったばっかなのに死にそうだぞ
(There are people around so if something happens, won't they blame me.)
人目があるし
Are you okay, Komari?
大丈夫か小鞠？
If anyone asks, make sure to tell them I was genuinely worried.
いざって時には
Die!
死ねえ
(Why am I being insulted when I'm so worried?)
こんなに心配しているのに なんで罵倒されるんだ
Oh, Komari-chan, there you are!
ああ小鞠ちゃんここにいた！
Sorry, sorry, I got carried away and ended up running to the other side.
ごめんごめん 勢い余って 反対側に走っちゃってさ
Yakishio, were you looking for Komari?
焼塩 お前小鞠を探してたのか
Yeah, I brought some water for Komari-chan.
うん小鞠ちゃんに お水持ってきたの
Here you go.
はいどうぞ
Thank you.
ありがとう
Why does it look like Komari-chan is about to collapse?
焼塩 なんで小鞠死にそうになってるんだ？
It's a bit dry today, you know.
今日ちょっと乾燥してるからね
Maybe she's thirsty because she ran all the way here.
ここまで走ってきたから 喉が渇いたのかな
From home?!!
家から？！！
It's 10 kilometers to get here!
ここまで10キロあるぞ！
I did carry her on my back for about half of the way, though.
半分くらいは あたしがおぶったんだけどな
Let's slow down the pace a bit on the way back, Komari-chan.
小鞠ちゃん帰りは ちょっとペース落とそっか
I'll... take the bus... on the way back...
帰りは…バス…使うから…
I told you we could use club funds for the bus fare, didn't I?
部費でバス代出すって言ったのに
Why did you run all the way here?
なんで走ってきたんだよ
Nukkun
ぬっくん
There's a destination.
目的地がある
And a path that leads there.
そこに繋がる道がある
And we've got two legs to get us there.
そしてあたしたちには 2本の足がある
We have to run, don't we?
走るしかないよね
Hey, be careful, you're starting to sound just like Yanami.
や、焼塩 八奈見（やなみ）とお、同じようなこと 言ってるから き、気をつけろ
Thanks for the water.
水ありがとう
Oh, that's Nukkun's.
あそれぬっくんのだよ
N-N-Nukkun's... water?!
ぬっぬっぬ、温水（ぬくみず）の… 飲みかけ？！
Uh, well, Yakishio suddenly showed up, so I didn't mean any harm.
えっと なんか急に焼塩が来たから 悪気があったわけじゃないぞ
Does it bother you that he's drunk from it?
飲みかけ嫌だった？
Sorry about that. I don't really mind.
ごめんね あたしはあんま気にしないからさ
Yeah, Nukkun, I took a sip too.
はい ぬっくん あたしも少しもらったよ
(Even though I accepted it, she drank from it, right?)
（受け取っちゃったけど これ飲みかけだよな）
(Throwing it away seems wasteful... maybe I'll just take it home...)
（捨てるのもなんだし 家に持って帰って…）
(Is it really okay to take home a drink that a girl has already drank from?)
（いや 女子の飲みかけを 持ち帰るのはどうなんだ？）
What's wrong, Nukkun? You're frozen.
どうしたのぬっくん？ 固まって
It's nothing!
なっなんでもない！
It's nothing. Maybe I'll have a drink too.
なんでもないから 俺も飲もうかな
G-Give it here!
よ、よこせ！
Komari-chan
小鞠ちゃん
Komari, you...
小鞠 お前…
Uh, um, well...
え、え、えっと…
Were you that thirsty?
そんなに喉乾いてたの？
Nukkun, do you think Komari-chan might have heatstroke?
ぬっくんひょっとして 小鞠ちゃん熱中症かも！
Got it! I'll go buy some drinks right away!
わかった！ すぐ飲み物買ってくる！
Uh, um, I'm okay...
あ、あの、もう だ、大丈夫?
Komari-chan, I'll carry you over to that chair!
小鞠ちゃん あたしがあそこの椅子まで 運んであげる！
Hang on, I'll go buy water right now!
待ってろ すぐ買ってくる！
That was refreshing, right?
はい、しみるでしょう
I've opened the second bottle too.
2本目のペットボトルも開けたよ
Does your head hurt?
頭は痛くないか？
How many fingers do you see?
この指何本に見える？
I-I'm fine.
だ、だ、大丈夫
I-I can't drink that many--
う、そ、そんなに何本も飲めない――
Yes, keep drinking!
はい、どんどん飲んで！
(I'm glad to see that Komari seems to have calmed down.)
（小鞠も 落ち着いてきたようでよかった）
(After all, Yakishio and I are well aware of the dangers of heatstroke.)
（何しろ俺と焼塩は 熱中症の恐ろしさをよく知っているのだ）
(By the way, I really didn't see anything then.)
（ちなみにあの時は 本当に見ていない）
(Probably.)
（たぶん）
(Believe me.)
（信じてくれ）
By the way, Nukkun, why are we meeting at a roadside station today?
それはそうとぬっくん 今日はなんで道の駅に集合したの？
Remember, I mentioned we were going to take the second round of photos for the website?
ほら、ホームページ用の写真 第2弾を撮るって言っただろ?
Yanami-san got really motivated.
八奈見さんがすっかりやる気になってさ
Hmm.
うーん
So, what about Yana-chan?
それで八奈ちゃんは？
We already took photos of Yanami-san the other day.
八奈見さんの写真は こないだ撮ったから
Besides, this is a roadside station, right?
それに、ここって道の駅だろ？
Hmm?
ん？
Why does that matter?
それがどうかしたの？
They have everything here, from local ingredients to gourmet foods.
ここには地元の食材から グルメまで全てが揃ってるんだ
What do you think would happen if we brought Yanami-san to a place like this?
こんなところに八奈見さんを 召喚したらどうなると思う？
Ah, it would get out of hand, wouldn't it?
あぁ、収集がつかなくなるね
Plus, this time, the costs for the photo shoot are covered by the club funds.
しかも今回は 撮影にかかるコストは部費で払うからな
If Yanami-san were here, the literary club's finances would be ruined!
八奈見さんがいたら 文芸部の財政は破綻する！
I see, that sounds tough!
なるほど、それは大変だ!
That's why today's photo shoot is a secret from Yanami-san.
だから今日の撮影は 八奈見さんには内緒なんだ
It's a photo shoot that absolutely can't be found out.
絶対にバレてはいけない 撮影会ってやつだな
K-K-Keeping it a secret?
な、な、内緒？
What's wrong, Komari-chan?
どうしたの、小鞠ちゃん？
N-Nothing at all.
な、なんでもない
It looks like Komari's feeling better now.
小鞠も元気になったみたいだし
Let's get started with the photo shoot.
早速撮影を始めようか
What are we going to shoot? Running?
撮影って何撮るの？走る？
Since we're at the roadside station, I thought we could take some photos of us enjoying the local gourmet food.
せっかく道の駅にいるんだし ご当地グルメを食べてるところを撮ろうかなって
Food really does make for great photos.
やっぱ映えには食べ物だ
Oh!
おぉ
You're starting to sound like Yanami, so be careful.
や、八奈見と同じようなこと言ってるから き、気を付けろ
But I don't really have that much money...
でも、私そんなにお金…
I told you, we'll pay for it with club funds.
言っただろ 部費で払うって
Oh!
おぉ！
Is it really okay to use it for something like that?
そ、そんなことに使っていいのか？
The first batch of photos for Yanami-san and even the cost for the canelé were covered by that too.
八奈見さんの写真の第一弾 カヌレの代金もそうだったんだぞ
Technically, she ate it all before we took the photo.
厳密には撮る前に全部食べたけど
What are you doing while you're supposed to be watching over her?
お、お前がついていながら 何やってんだ？
Huh, is it my fault?
え、俺のせい?
Nukkun, aren't you in charge of Yana-chan?
ぬっくん、八奈ちゃん担当でしょ？
I'm in charge of doting on Komari-chan.
あたしは小鞠ちゃん 可愛がる担当だし
Hey, stop it! Don't mess up my hair!
うぇー、こ、こら 髪の毛、わしゃわしゃするな
So, I was in charge of Yanami-chan?
俺、八奈見係だったのか
I wish I could switch roles.
担当変わってほしい
Wow, there's a lot to choose from!
おぉ、いろいろあるね！
It smells like delicious bread too.
パンのいい匂いもするし
Oh, there's popcorn too!
あっ、ポップコーンもあるよー!
Yakishio, don't run too much.
焼塩、あんまり走るなよ
N-Nukumizu, are you sure it's really okay to have anything?
ぬ、温水 ほ、本当 なんでもいいのか?
Ah.
あぁ
Considering Yanami-san's antics, a snack or two is nothing at all.
八奈見さんのやりたい放題を思えば おやつの一つや二つ、なんでもない
How about we have some Toyohashi curry udon?
なんなら 豊橋カレーうどんでも食べるか？
That's something only Yanami would consider a snack.
そ、それ、おやつにするのは 八奈見くらいだ
For her, even dessert after a meal is nothing.
あいつなら食後のデザートもな
W-well, then, I... I want to try the soft serve from that gelato shop over there.
じゃ、じゃあ、私 あ、あそこのジェラート屋のそ、ソフトクリーム食べたい
Sure, but I didn't know you like soft serve.
いいけど ソフトクリーム好きなんだ
W-well, when I go out with my family...
そ、ソフトクリーム か、家族で出かけると
The little one often gets to have it bought for them, but, I find it hard to say I want something like that.
ち、ちびすけはよく買ってもらってるけど
Alright, eat as much as you like.
よし、いくらでも食べてくれ
Should we order two? One for each hand!
二つ頼むか、両手持ちもいいぞ
One is enough.
ひ、ひとつでいい
If Yanami were more like this, she wouldn't have been rejected.
八奈見もこれくらいの健気さがあれば 振られなかったのに
But still, even Komari got rejected.
いやでも、小鞠は振られたし
I guess when you're going to get rejected, you're going to get rejected.
振られるときは振られるということか
Hey, Nukkun!
おーい、ぬっくん！
I'll go with this one.
あたしはこれにするよ
Adult's First Love Lemon... Lemonade, huh?
大人の初恋レモン レモネードか
It's kind of stylish.
なんかおしゃれだな
I thought that maybe I should take a cue from Yanami-chan and try to be more conscious of what's Instagram-worthy.
あたしも八奈ちゃん見習って 映えを意識してみようかなって
The name is stylish too, isn't it? "Adult's First Love Lemon."
名前もおしゃれじゃん？ 大人の初恋レモン
First love...
初恋…
First love is supposed to be a bit sour, after all.
初恋って酸っぱいものだからね
Alright, let's buy it! I'm going to get it right away!
よし、それ買おう！ 早速買うぞ！
Nukkun, aren't you going to buy one?
ぬっくんは買わなくていいの?
Me? I'm the photographer, after all.
俺？俺は撮影係だから
Why not?
いいじゃん
I'll go with Komari-chan to find some good photo spots outside.
あたしと小鞠ちゃんが 外で撮影スポット探しとくから
Nukkun, make sure to buy yourself something you want too.
ぬっくんも何か欲しいの買っといてよ
Don't hold back...
え、遠慮するな
Oh, got it.
ああ、わかった
Even though I said that, I'm not sure what to buy.
とは言ったものの 何を買おうかな
Come to think of it, Yanami mentioned before that the chikuwa quail egg fry here is absolutely delicious.
そういえば、八奈見が前に ちくわうずらフライが絶品だと言ってたな
I'm pretty sure I saw it over here earlier.
確かさっきこっちで見かけたぞ
Oh, this is the place.
おっ、この店だ
Excuse me, I'd like one chikuwa quail egg fry, please.
すいません ちくわうずらフライを一つ
Huh?
え？
Did it just sell out?
今売り切れたところなんですか？
Oh, okay. I'll come back later.
ああ、はい また後で来ます
There were so many just a moment ago.
さっきまでたくさんあったのに
I wonder who bought them all.
誰が買い占めたんだろう
A group of quail enthusiasts, maybe?
うずら好きの団体客か
Or maybe a competitive eater?
フードファイターでも来たのか
Alright then.
さてと
We need to get this shoot done quickly.
早いとこ撮影しないとな
The two of them are at a table on the terrace.
二人は…
Sorry to keep you waiting.
お待たせ
Is it good?
それおいしいか
Th-the soft serve is delicious.
そ、ソフトクリーム、おいしい
This lemonade is delicious too!
このレモネードもおいしいよー
It's got a lot going on, kind of like a grown-up taste, don't you think?
なんかいろいろあった 大人の味って感じだよね
Nukkun, do you want a sip too?
ぬっくんも一口飲む?
(This is it, the perfect moment.)
（きた、この瞬間だ）
Ugh, what's going on all of a sudden?
うえ、ん、なんだ、いきなり
This is it, the perfect moment for a photo.
今、最高のシャッターチャンスが 降りてきたんだ
Look at this photo.
見てくれ、この写真
Oh, that's great!
おお、いいじゃん
Komari-chan's smile is super cute!
小鞠ちゃんの笑顔 めっちゃかわいいよ！
I-I feel kind of embarrassed.
な、なんだか、恥ずかし
There's nothing to be embarrassed about!
恥ずかしがることなんてない
The photo capturing a childlike smile along with Yakishio offering the lemonade...
子供のような笑みを 切り取った一枚は
It's building a story.
一つのストーリーを構築しているんだ
That's right...
そうだな
It really resembles that scene in an anime I was watching the other day, when a girl who lost her heart...
こないだ見たアニメだと
...smiled for the first time while eating sweets given by the protagonist.
生まれて初めて笑顔を 見せた感動のシーンによーく似ている
It seems like there might be some demand for that kind of photo...
なんだかそっち方面の需要も ありそうな一枚だな
D-delete it!
け、消せ！
In fact, delete yourself!
むしろお前が、消えろ！
Nukkun, that was a bit creepy.
ぬっくん、今のはちょっとキモいよ
(I thought I was giving a compliment.)
（褒めたつもりだったのに）
(It's really hard to compliment girls.)
（女子を褒めるのって難しいな）
I think it turned out well.
よく撮れてると思うけど
The table is lined with delicious-looking food.
テーブルの上に 美味しそうな食べ物が並んでいるのも
Huh?
あれ？
When did we buy so much?
いつの間にこんなに買ったんだ？
And this bag looks familiar...
それにこのバッグは見覚えを…
Ah, that's...
あー、それは…
Komari...
小鞠…
Why did you suddenly look away?
なんで急に目をそらした？
Uh, well...
え、えっと…
I-I told Yanami that we were coming here...
こ、ここに来るって八奈見に… 言った
Huh?
え
You told her?
言ったの？
I didn't know, Nukumizu, that you were planning to leave Yanami out...
だって、温水が八奈見 な、仲間外れにするって知らなかったから…
The way you said that...
言い方…
So that means...
ってことは…
Is all this food because Yanami-san is here?
この大量の食べ物は 八奈見さんが来てるのか？
Here, now?!
今、ここに？！
Yeah, she said something about giving you an earful before leaving to find you.
うん、なんか、ぬっくんを 懲らしめるとか言って探し回ってるよ
To teach you a lesson!
わ、分からせられる
Did I do something wrong?
俺、なんか悪いことしたっけ？
Is she going to scold me?
分からせられるの？
It's Yanami-san!
や、八奈見さんだ
Oh, you hung up.
あ、電話切った
Are you running?
に、逃げるのか！
Of course I'm running! She's scary!
もちろん逃げるぞ だって怖いし
Oh, it's Yana-chan! Hey!
あ、八奈ちゃんだ、おーい！
Alright, then, I'll leave the rest to you!
あ、じゃあ、 あとは任せだ！
C-Coward!
ひ、卑怯者！
(I managed to blend into the crowd and make my escape)
（人混みに紛れて なんとか逃げ切った俺は）
(As I get on the bus, I can't help but sigh)
（バスに乗り込みながら 思わずため息をつく）
(It took an hour one way,)
（片道1時間かけて、）
(I was only there for 15 minutes)
（滞在時間は15分）
(What was the point of going there?)
（一体、何しに行ったんだ？）
(Well, at least I got the photo...)
（一応写真は撮れたけど…）
(That Komari...)
（小鞠のやつ…）
(She looks really happy.)
（なんか幸せそうな顔してるな）
(Well, let's say that getting that expression made this whole thing worth it.)
（まあ、この顔を撮れただけでも いいとするか…）